

Mukesh Kumar Ranjan

BACKEND DEVELOPER



WHO AM I AT A GLANCE

I am a Back-end web developer with a solid understanding of web fundamentals and back-end development. Also, having a multidisciplinary background that includes coding, design and documentation with relevant industry experience in search engine optimisation including multiple projects utilising my team management skills.

WHY HIRE ME?

- I'm a **result-oriented** web application developer with considerable training and hands-on projects based experience in all stages of design, coding, and testing of web applications.
- Ready to solve real world problems with in the formation, planning, and implementation of Backend API that meets the MVP features.
- To **serve the objective of business** along with the growth of organisation and to be a good personnel.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

#SCHOOL OF ACCELERATED LEARNING, HYD Product Engineering - (June - December) 2020

• Completed and Graduated with all the 11 MVP's built using Javascript and Node Js framework technology.

#PUNJAB TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, JALANDHAR Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering - August 2010 to June 2014

• Graduated with a bachelors degree that equipped me with the knowledge of web fundamentals, programming languages and operating systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#CONCENTRIX DAKSH SERVICES INDIA PVT. LTD. Senior Advisor | April 2017 to February 2020

- Worked on Multiple Client Projects including "Machine Learning", "Revue Tool Testing" & "Hate Speech Policy" while applying my knowledge and technical skills.
- Researching ideas and preparing drafts for validation.

Bucket Lead - Ad Words | June 2015 to March 2017

• Managed team size of 12-15 members, responsible for policy training, to review the assigned tasks for each members and **presenting reports** to the **management**.

#INNOVATIVE TRAINING PLACE, NEW DELHI SEO & Data Analyst | November 2014 to May 2015

- Handled web development and Client SEO Activities.
- Worked on 20 applications & Managed databases.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

• Web Technologies - Frameworks - DataBases JavaScript Express Js Mongo DB HTML Node Is PostgreSQL

• Web Servers - Version Control - Cloud Platform **NGINX** Github Heroku Github Pages **AWS** Amazon EC2

Additional Technical Competencies

CSS Web Sockets Search Engine Optimisation Shell Scripting Open Source MySQL MVC Design

HANDS-ON PROJECTS

#WEBDEVPOOL - A DEVELOPERS COMMUNITY Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Mongo DB

- Built a professional network for developers where they can share their skills, experiences, education and showcase their 5 recent github repositories with other developers worldwide.
- Users can create their profiles, publish posts, like posts and can make comments in post.
- Created Back-end API and worked on integration for the webdevpool application.
- Managed the team and designed the website wire-framing from the scratch with the idea.

#AUTHORSBLOG - A BLOGGING PLATFORM Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Mongo DB

- Built a guest blogging platform for authors and bloggers who want to promote their online business by writing articles in this platform.
- Users can sign-in/up, create their profiles and publish their posts, comment and like also.
- Lead the team, designed the website wire-framing and created back-end API for product.

#IMGUP - AN IMAGE UPLOADING APPLICATION

Node Js, React Js, Express Js, Firebase

- Simulated the popular image sharing web application imgur.com.
- Users can upload single or multiple images and after that they will get a notification in the bar.
- Created the entire back-end API, Integrated frontend and done testing for this web application.

(Dial: (+91) 783-881-0985

